第九集  冲突
EPISODE 9 THE RUN-IN
有一些品质，如果缺少的话，你很难赢得比赛
There are a few qualities that, without them, you just can’t win.
其中最需要花时间培养的就是心理素质
The one that takes more time to develop is the psychological profile,
作为一个集体去比赛的精气神
that collective state of mind.
这帮小伙子现在最缺的就是这个
I think that is something that they really need to improve.
行了
OK.
我们来谈谈下一场比赛
Let’s move to the next game.
从防守端来说
By the defensive point of view,
咱就保持一贯的作风
we want to keep the same principles,
但是咱们得往前提20米
but we need to do it 20 metres more in front.
所有人，锋线、中场、后防线都得往前提
Everybody, strikers, midfielders, defensive line bring it up.
人家铁定摆我们大巴，所以说会很难踢，很难
They are very defensive, so difficult match... difficult match.
咱们还有八场比赛要踢
So, eight matches to play.
如果出于某种原因，我们没法拿到积分榜第五
If for some reason, we don’t manage to get that fifth position,
虽然我是觉得没啥可能，但是万一失足
which I think we can, there is still the position
咱还有欧联，如果我们去踢欧联杯
of Europa League. If we play Europa League,
咱也还有机会能赢，总之比啥都没有强，所以说
maybe we win it, maybe it’s better than not to play so...
接下来还是得去争取
We still have fights in there.
积分榜第五跟第六已经近在咫尺了
Fifth is there and for the sixth is there.
咱再冲一把
Here we go.
托特纳姆热刺的新时代到来了
A new era begins for Tottenham Hotspur.
最重要的东西是
The most important thing...
勇气
Courage.
忠诚
Honesty.
亲如家人
Family.
聆听来自托特纳姆热刺球场的山呼海啸吧
Listen to Tottenham Hotspur's Stadium now.
小伙子们，冲起来！干他丫的！
Let’s go together, boys. Come on!
好，开始吧，球在那
OK, let’s go! Balls there.
两天后，热刺将与西汉姆联展开伦敦德比大战
In two days time, Tottenham Hotspur will face West Ham in a London derby.
两队的上一次交手恰逢穆帅的首秀
The two sides last met in José Mourinho’s first game as Head Coach.
我能感受到些许的不同
I can feel little differences,
这是个过程，我们在慢慢变化
it’s a process, I say that we are changing.
这个过程需要时间
It’s a process that takes time.
我督促他们形成这种责任感
I push them for... for this sense of responsibility.
对球迷的责任感，还有对俱乐部的责任感
Responsibility to the fans, to the club.
这非常非常重要。我觉得…
It’s something very, very important. I think it’s...
这一定程度上决定了球队是否更加具有竞争力
it's part of a certain package that makes a team more or less competitive.
热刺本赛季还有八场比赛
Spurs have eight matches remaining this season.
他们目前排名联赛第八，距离第五还差四分
They currently sit in eighth, four points off fifth position,
而第五就足以可能让热刺挺进下赛季的欧冠
which could be enough to secure Champions League football
如果曼城的禁令维持原判
if Manchester City’s ban remains in place.
我觉得这是一场极度重要的比赛
I think this is a desperately important game.
热刺已经连续七场不胜了
Spurs are winless in seven games.
我仍然认为第五还是有希望的
I still think fifth is certainly feasible.
我们需要赢下今晚这场比赛
We need to win this game tonight.
伦敦德比！伙计们！
London derby lads, alright?
加油！加油兄弟们！
Come on, come on, boys!
一场首都德比战已然打响
A derby in the capital is up and running.
被绍切克抢断
Just cut out by Soucek.
洛塞尔索，拿住球
Take the ball, Gio.
软趴趴的跟坨翔一样！
It’s too flat this shit.
鲍文
Bowen...
一路火花带闪电交给插上的费雷德里克斯
Electric play brings Fredericks into it.
福纳尔斯在中苏，安东尼奥在后点包抄
Fornals is in the middle, Antonio’s round the back post...
上啊，埃里克森！
Come on, Eric!
洛塞尔索拿回球权
Lo Celso retrieves it.
好球！孙哥位置不错！
Good ball...Son in a really good area...
孙兴慜为热刺首开纪录
And Heung-min Son has fired Spurs ahead.
但我估计这球不算，看起来孙兴慜好像越位了
But I do not think this will stand, it looks like Son is offside.
进球无效
And it is not a goal.
进入中场休息
Half time.
好，开始吧
OK, let's go.
如果有人
If any one of you
感觉有点累
feels a little bit of fatigue,
想想你们休息了三天，他们只有两天休息
you had three days to rest, they have two days to rest.
我不觉得这是累，我不觉得
I don’t think it's fatigue, I don’t think it is.
如果你们需要点压力才能踢好
If you need a little bit of pressure to be better,
那我就来给你们点实实在在的压力
I give you an honest little bit of pressure.
如果咱们这场赢不下来，咱就完犊子了
I think if we don’t win the game, it’s over.
整个歇逼
It’s over.
什么第四也好，第五也罢
Forget fourth, forget fifth,
想都别想
it’s over.
我们今儿的这些雄心壮志，人一脚就能给我们踢飞了
Our ambitions today, they can finish.
然后我们还得再踢一个月
And then we are going to have one more month
嘴里含着一口屎再踢七场
with seven more matches to, uh, to... to play with a shit feeling.
你们得再加把劲儿
You have to give more.
得再拼的狠一点
你们还能再精进的地方我能说一千个
I can tell you one thousand details where you have to give more.
咱现在最大的问题是
Our biggest problem is one...
瞎几把传然后把球丢了
missing shit passes.
又他妈软，又他妈慢，该往前送的时候在那回传
Fucking sloppy, fucking slow, pass back when the pass should be in front.
瞎他妈传
It's sloppy.
第二个问题是不够紧张
The second thing is about intensity.
你们要么是责任感不够强  要么就是动力不足
It’s about your responsibility or your own motivation.
这话我们踢第一场比赛之前我就说过
The game, I told this before we start playing the first game,
我早就说，你们老是踢完了才意识到比赛有多重要
I told you, you only have the feeling that the game was important in the end,
等比完了你们回到这里
and in the end of the game you are going to be here.
开始在那阿巴阿巴阿巴阿巴
Abababiya, abababa, abababa, abababa
大鼻涕流到嘴里知道甩了，踢的时候去干屁了
It’s not after the game, it’s during the game.
踢比赛的时候就给我想着：每一场比赛都非常重要，操！
It’s during the game. The game is important, fuck!
听到没有啊！
Hey!
- 上啊兄弟们！   - 操他们大爷的！
- Come on then lads, hey! - Fucking hell!
都他妈的醒醒！跟他们死磕到底！
Wake up hey, come on! Push!
加油兄弟们！跟他们干！
Come on then, let's go!
北伦敦的这场对决继续进行
We're back up and running in North London.
戴尔拿球，持续推进
It’s into Dier, stepping forward here,
埃里克·戴尔有机会！
Eric Dier into a good area.
逼抢！
Push!
传给德勒·阿里…
To Dele Alli...
凯恩打门！
Kane fires for goal!
加油！上啊小孙！加油小孙！
Come on, come on Sonny, come on Sonny!
孙兴慜，全场最快的球员之一，分边给到洛塞尔索
Son, one of the quickest players on the pitch, moves it out to Lo Celso.
凯恩就位了，打门！
Kane is there...Kane is in...
凯恩的射门稍稍偏出
And Kane has fired wide.
奥里耶传中
Aurier hangs it in.
巴尔武埃纳将球顶出，角球
And Balbuena nodding it behind for a corner.
噢，球被撞入了球门
Oh, and it’s scrambled in.
托特纳姆热刺首开纪录！
Tottenham Hotspur have the lead,
皮球碰到了一名西汉姆联球员折射
flicking off a West Ham player.
热刺向前推进，凯恩并不越位
Spurs looking to move on here and Kane is onside,
边裁没有举旗， 凯恩将比分改写为2-0
the flag has stayed down for Harry Kane to make it two-nil.
冷静的一锤定音
An outstandingly cool finish
来自凯恩在热刺的第200场英超比赛
from Harry Kane in his 200th Premier League appearance for Spurs.
这粒进球也为热刺锁定一场关键的胜利
And it wrapped up a big win for Tottenham Hotspur.
牛逼啊兄弟们！
Come on boys!
抱歉我想问一个今天没有出场的球员
Sorry to ask you about a player who didn’t play,
尤其是你今天还取得了胜利
especially after you’ve just come away with a victory,
但是我注意到汤基·恩东贝莱
but I noticed Tanguy Ndombele
今晚的比赛中压根都没有热身过
didn’t warm up at all tonight during the match.
一分钟都没上，你俩的关系还好吗？
Has Tanguy been okay with you not getting any minutes?
我没办法一场比赛首发12个或者13个球员
I cannot start a game with 12 or 13 players.
我尽力为球队作出最好的选择
I try to do the best for the team.
就，你知道
Uh... You know,
有时候我得向不是我第一选择的球员道歉
sometimes I apologise to my players that are not my first choice,
但是我得尽力做好我的工作
but I have to do my job the best I... the best I can.
- 好的，非常感谢大家  - 谢谢
- Right guys, thank you very much. - Thank you.
顶着6000万欧元的身价
At a reported 60 million euros,
汤基·恩东贝莱是热刺队史最高身价
Tanguy Ndombele is the most expensive player in Tottenham’s history.
转会费金额巨大，是一笔超级签约
The fee is huge, it’s a mega signing.
就像是董事会展示雄心所摆出的态度
It is a statement of intent from the Board.
这位23岁的法国人到来之后取得了一个梦幻开局
The 23-year-old Frenchman made an impressive start at the club,
首秀即进球
scoring on his debut.
汤基·恩东贝莱！立竿见影的效果！
Tanguy Ndombele, what an impact!
但自从首秀之后，汤基就饱受伤病困扰
But since then, Tanguy has struggled with injuries
也逐渐失去了常规首发地位
and has failed to establish a regular first team place.
其他队友都在帮助他适应伦敦的生活
Other members of the squad have been helping him adapt to life in London.
他和同胞，法国国脚穆萨·西索科的关系尤为亲密
He has built a bond with fellow French international, Moussa Sissoko.
汤基跟我属于是，他就像我的小老弟一样
My relationship with Tanguy is, he is like my little brother
我尽可能帮他
and uh, I try to help him.
作为一个球员，每场比赛你都想踢
When you’re a player you want to play every game,
想要享受足球，做好自己的工作
try to enjoy, try to do your job.
所以每当你进不了大名单
So when you are not being picking in the team
只是在训练，你能感觉到少了点什么
but just only training you can feel something is missing
这种感觉非常痛苦
and, uh, it’s very painful.
我完全可以理解这种感觉，因为我也经历过
I can understand because I've been in that situation
我知道的…这种感觉不好受
and I know it's... it's not a good feeling
有时候你回到家，满脑子还是在想着这个事
so even when you go back home you are still thinking about it.
穆萨，调酒大师
Moussa, the barman.
怎么样，味道不错吧
They’re good, aren’t they?
这个酱料不错，带一点点辣
I like the sauce, it’s a bit spicy.
有点像贝涅饼（一种法式传统油炸面团）
It’s kind of like beignets.
热着好吃，等凉了你要是再热一下
When they’re warm I like it, but when they’re cold and you reheat them,
那就是两种味了，感觉不一样的
it’s not the same eh, It’s another sensation.
还有这个酱饭（科特迪瓦传统美食）
And ‘Riz couché.’
对，就叫“Riz couché”，隔夜饭拌一拌
‘Riz couché, ’ that’s the thing, rice that has slept.
你第一个赛季感觉怎么样
Your first season, how's it been?
怎么说呢
What can I say?
一言难尽，我老是受伤
It’s been complicated, I was injured a lot.
还在过渡期适应比赛
It’s been a season of adaptation.
不过也还行，哥几个一直都在帮我
But it’s been OK, you guys have been there to help me.
你觉得适应起来哪方面会比较困难？
Why did you think it was difficult to settle in?
生活在异国他乡很复杂的
It’s complicated when you change country.
我离开法国
I left France,
离开我的家人来到这里
and I left my family to come here.
环境改变之后终归不是那么简单的
Then it’s not easy when you change environment.
训练的强度变大了，比赛更是
The training, it's a change in intensity, and even the matches.
人得学着适应新生活
You have to adapt to a new life,
到目前为止并不容易，但是慢慢来吧
and it hasn’t been easy so far but that’s how it is.
你知道，队伍里有20，25个球员
You know in the squad we are twenty, twenty five players, so,
所以不是每个球员都能一直上场的，这很正常，但是
so, of course, everyone cannot be on the pitch every time but you need to...
你得保持专注，努力做好本职工作，每天都试着进步一点点
to stay focused, try to do your job and try to improve every day,
我一直就是这么过来的
so that’s what I’ve tried to do and...
即使有时候很艰难，我也能保持耐心
I was patient even if sometime was hard,
一步一步来，最后进入首发十一人名单，所以说
and step by step I could make my place in the starting eleven, so...
困难的时候想要放弃是很轻松的
'Cause you know it’s easy to give up when it’s tough,
不仅是足球，生活里也是一样
not even in football but in the life.
人生就是一场阅历，对吧？
The life is experience, no?
最好的办法就是，你每天的努力都让自己满意
The best way to work, when you are happy with what you give,
训练的每一天都倾尽全力
uh, everyday in the training,
你懂的，剩下的就是等待时机的到来
you know, yeah, you need to wait the right moment.
教练做决定的时候，咱们得学会接受
When the manager is making some choice and... we need to accept that
即使有时候是痛苦的
even if sometime it’s painful.
不过汤基明年就能带咱们挺进欧冠
But Tanguy will bring us to the Champions League next year.
没错，我们都相信他
Yeah, we believe on him.
你为什么想当球员？
Why did you want to become a footballer?
因为，我喜欢足球
Because, uh, I love football.
After speaking with José,
和魔力鸟谈过之后
主席列维把他的转会标王叫来开了个会
chairman Daniel Levy calls a meeting with his record signing
来讨论他上场时间不够的问题
to discuss his lack of playing time.
我总是说，转会这个事儿
I always say to people when it comes to transfers
你是在跟不同的球员打交道，他们来自五湖四海不同的俱乐部
you're dealing with human beings, they're in a different club,
拥有不同的文化，你没办法完全保证
a different culture and there's absolutely no guarantee
每个人在我们这也能玩得转
that they’ll work in this club.
有时候也需要一点运气，正确的判断，还有很多细致的工作
We need a little bit of luck, some good judgement and a lot of hard work.
来啦伙计，就是这儿
Ah voila, it’s here my friend. Here it is.
列维让球员联络官罗伯托·巴尔邦廷加入讨论
He’s asked player liaison officer Roberto Balbontin to join them.
他来了，还有两分钟马上到
He’s coming. He’ll be here in two minutes.
罗伯托会说四种语言
Roberto speaks four languages,
非常擅长帮助球员适应新俱乐部
and specialises in helping players settle at the club.
对于汤基来说，转会而来是个艰难的转变
For Tanguy, it’s been a difficult transition for him.
- 嘿，丹尼尔  - 嘿
- Hey, Daniel. - Hi.
通常来说，球员需要6-8个月来适应新环境
Normally, it takes about six months to eight months for someone to settle in
但是具体来说因人而异
but everybody is different.
好嘞，那么…
OK, so...
来跟我说说，到底是哪里出了问题
tell me, give me the story of what’s... what’s not working.
你在我们这有哪些不适应的
What doesn’t work for you here with us?
过去的三个月我都在很努力的训练
For three months I trained hard.
大家都说我训练表现的非常好
Everybody says I trained really well,
但我依然上不了场，意味着还有别的问题
but if I don’t play it means there must be something else.
大多数球员，奔赴海外踢球的第一个赛季
Many players, in their first season coming from overseas,
都很艰难，这很正常
found it difficult and it is normal.
你所经历的事情没啥大不了的
The experiences that you’ve had are normal.
穆萨，你俩熟得很，这小子刚来的时候
Moussa, obviously, he knows Moussa well, he came to Tottenham
表现的也是一塌糊涂
and was very disappointing in the early period
但是我跟他说，我知道你能表现的更好
and I said to him, "I know you are a better player than you are showing
但是你得决定你脑子里想的是什么
but you have to decide where... what’s in your head."
穆萨有一点很好的是，这小子天生争强好斗
The nice thing about Moussa, Moussa is an absolute fighter.
他并不打算离开这家俱乐部
He was not prepared to leave the club.
我确实专注度不够
I’m not concentrating as I should be.
没拿出满分的状态
I am not 100%.
我16岁那会儿，还在上学的时候
When I was at school, when I was 16, OK?
有一次家长会
My... at a parents' evening,
我班主任跟我爸妈说
um, my headteacher told my parents
我应该退学了
I should leave school.
第二天，我跟自己说，“他大爷的，我不能就这么认输了”
The next day, I said to myself, "I am not going to be beaten."
然后从那一天起
and from that moment onwards,
我门门考试一路得A，顺利考上大学
I got "A" s in my exams and I went to university.
我是个斗士
I am a fighter.
我也是个都是，我一直都在拼搏
I’m a fighter, I’ve always fought.
我今天能在这里都是我拼来的
I'm here today because I fought.
无论是踢球还是生活我都没放弃过
I have never given up in football or in life.
俱乐部，包括教练
We the club, and the manager,
我们都对他的天赋深信不疑
we both believe he has the talent.
只有他自己才能解锁自己的天赋，扭转局面
He has to unlock it, only he can turn that around.
汤基，就像他说的，你得靠自己挺过这一关
Like he said, Tanguy, it’s for you to overcome this thing.
他来自法国的体系，所有东西都得重新学
It’s all learning because he’s come from a system in France
那个体系他很熟
where he knew everything.
不能指望球员来了就能形成即战力，即来即用
You can’t expect people to just kind of like plonk them in somewhere and go,
“你要啥有啥，开干吧”
"Go on you’ve got all the tools, get on with it."
人不是机器，不是这么来的
It doesn’t work like that.
第一年总是很复杂的，我的朋友
The first year is very complicated, my friend.
当你迈过这道坎，前面就是未来，身后的都是过往
Put a line under it. This is the future, that is the past
抬头向前看吧
and look ahead.
OK，行，谢谢啦
OK alright, thank you.
我觉得穆萨这样的人
I think having someone like Moussa,
他是我共事过最温和的球员
he's one of the kindest players I work with,
穆萨从被从球迷所嘲笑，到成为球队的大腿
Moussa went from derided by fans, to one of the top players at the club.
汤基在经历同样的过程，他最终也会变成大腿的，只是需要一些时间
Tanguy is on that process and he’ll get there, it just takes time.
打门！射！
Finish, finish!
热刺的下一场比赛，是客场挑战谢菲联的一场硬仗
Next up for Tottenham, is a difficult away fixture at Sheffield United.
明天就是汤基·恩东贝莱转会一周年了
Tomorrow is the first anniversary since the signing of Tanguy Ndombele,
客观来说这笔转会目前来说还不可谓成功
I think it’s fair to say the move probably hasn’t yet worked out.
还要怎么做他本人才能发挥出来呢
What needs to happen and what does he have to do?
能不能给我们讲讲他的性格，换句话说，他是一个自省的人吗？
Just give us an insight into his mentality and, in other words, is he self critical?
这个问题不应该问我，你们应该问他
That’s not a question for me, that’s a question for him.
一个球员要是没有天赋，那屁用没有
Nothing happens when the players have no talent.
但是一旦有点天赋，很多事情都会不一样的
When you have talent, lots of things can... can change
一切皆有可能
and lots of things can... can happen.
赛前两队在积分榜上只差一分
Going into the match, just one point separates the two sides.
这场比赛热刺必须拿下，如果他们
It’s a must win game if Spurs are to keep pace
还想继续竞争下赛季的欧冠席位的话
with the other Champions League contenders.
谢菲尔德联1，托特纳姆热刺0
Sheffield United one, Tottenham Hotspur nil.
大家一起上啊！冲啊！
Let's go, come on, come on!!
热刺试图迅速给予反击
Spurs looking to respond swiftly.
小卢卡斯·莫拉在中路突破
Lucas Moura breaking through the middle of the pitch,
他好像被踢到了，哈里·凯恩拿到球…
I think he was caught there. Spurs will play on...
热刺还在进攻
through Harry Kane.
噢！来自凯恩的华丽一击！
Oh, it’s majestic from Kane,
其他人还在看裁判的反应，仓促地跑过去试图给予裁判压力
with others looking at the referee and scrambling to get back defensively.
VAR正在检查是否存在手球
Well, they are checking this for hand ball,
这未免也有点太过严苛了
that would be exceptionally harsh you feel.
进球被取消了吗？
Has this been ruled out?
看样子是取消了，球好像碰到了卢卡斯·莫拉的手臂
Looks like it has, they’re saying this has hit the arm of Lucas Moura.
进球无效，比分维持1-0
Goal disallowed, it stays one-nil.
你可以看到热刺球员难以置信的表情
You can see the disbelief from the Tottenham players,
这是怎么给吹掉的
how can that not be given?
未免有点太严格了
It is very, very harsh.
精神点，小伙子们！打起精神来！
Liven up, boys! Come on!
你们他妈的在训练场的拼劲呢！来这梦游来了！
You are more intense in the fucking training session than in here.
行，那是进球，行，裁判是个瞎子
OK, was a goal. OK, it’s a disgrace.
被判定无效简直是他妈奇耻大辱，那又怎样呢
OK, it’s a fucking big disgrace that this is not a goal,
现实就是，你们还得接着踢
but the reality is the game is there.
热刺需要在下半场展开攻势
Spurs need a massive second half here.
现在我们0-1输人家一个，我们得防守
So we are losing one-zero and we have to defend,
如果你们继续梦游，如果防守不够给力
if we lose concentration, if we don’t defend
人家进咱们第二个如探囊取物
they score a second goal.
淦他马勒戈壁的！
Fucking hell!
德勒·阿里和汤基·恩东贝莱准备好上场了
Dele Alli and Tanguy Ndombele are being prepared.
如果你的当家转会标王踢不上比赛
It is always going to be a big talking point
一定会成为大家讨论的热点的
when your record signing isn’t playing matches.
列维肯定要跟穆里尼奥说
And obviously Daniel Levy is going to be saying to him,
“大哥，6500万大洋啊大哥，你给我好好用起来啊”
"Sixty-five million quid, José, you know, get a tune out of him."
恩东贝莱，漂亮
Ndombele, nicely done.
拉梅拉…
Lamela...
过顶球倒找孙兴慜，后者成功回传到门前
can hang it round the back for Son, who does cut it back successfully
哈里·凯恩打进了！
and Harry Kane has got his goal.
凯恩在伤停补时阶段的进球并没有给热刺带来多大的安慰
Harry Kane’s injury time goal provides Spurs with little consolation.
比赛结束了
And the game is over.
这场失利使得热刺的欧冠梦疑云密布
This defeat puts a massive dent in their Champions League hopes.
- 艰难的一晚，是吧若泽？  - 确实
- Tough night, José? - Yeah.
老实说，我本以为我们可以简单把锅甩在
To be honest, I think it would be very, very easy
迈克尔·奥利弗的判罚问题上
to just speak about Michael Oliver decision,
但是那粒进球的取消不应该杀死我们的
but that goal disallowed cannot kill us.
我们有足够的时间，在心理上作为一只团结的队伍给予回应
We had enough time to psychologically react as a team in a different way,
而不是因为一个判罚问题就歇菜
and don’t die with that decision,
这口大锅得我们自己来背
and that's the thing I blame ourselves
我们得在精神层面变得更加强大
because we have to be much, much mentally stronger
才能从容面对今天这种场面
to cope with situations like this.
比赛踢得非常糟糕，队员的态度也很糟糕，没得洗
The game was really bad. The attitude was really bad, it’s true.
他们得为此有个交代
They have to give an answer.
每天我都在更加了解我的球员们
Every day I learn more about my players,
他们赢球会怎么样，输球会怎么样
what they are winning a match, what they are losing a match,
大败而归又会怎样
what they are after a defeat.
我是个要求很高的人
I am very demanding
嗯…
and, uh...
我总是试图把球员推到极限
I try to push players to... to their limits
我也支持球员内部的竞争
and I like to feed that internal competition.
输给谢菲联的三天之后
Three days after the defeat against Sheffield United,
穆里尼奥决定让球员们分成11对11
José decides that he wants to see his players
来一场真刀真枪的队内对抗赛
in an eleven-a-side match against each other.
准备！开始！冲啊！
OK, ready! Go, go, go!
没错！紧逼！
Yes! Push, push!
绕到前面去！塞尔吉！
Go over! Go over, Serge!
加油！
Come on!
嘿！犯规了！
Hey! Hey, it's a foul!
靠老好人是没办法赢下比赛的
You don’t win football matches with nice guys
你踏上赛场的时候就得带着这种觉悟
and you have to go to the competition with that spirit.
你还行不？
You, OK?
我认为他他在一步步的试图让我们理解
I think step by step he tried to make us understand
他心中对我们期待的踢法
the way he wants us to play.
我觉得他的足球哲学，是以侵略性的踢法为核心的
I think his philosophy is to play football with aggressiveness,
看到他的球员在场上拼尽全力
to see your players giving everything on the pitch,
这比什么的都重要
it’s more important than anything else.
埃里克·戴尔凶狠放铲孙兴慜，导致后者需要接受治疗
A hard tackle by Eric Dier, leaves Heung-min Son needing treatment.
随着比赛继续，更紧张的冲突在队内爆发了
And as play continues, more tension breaks out within the squad.
你就整天在那叨逼叨，每天都是
You speak a lot, every day you speak a lot,
就剩个破嘴，一天天的就他妈知道嘚巴嘚嘚巴嘚嘚巴嘚
you speak a lot every day, every day you speak a lot, every day...
可以了！打住！
OK! Stop!
小孙刚刚倒下了
Sonny’s just gone down.
- 啥意思？小孙倒了？  - 不是，他刚刚给铲翻了
- What do you mean gone down? - No, he's just been knocked down, now.
- 他绝逼是故意的，你说是不是？  - 谁？教练吗？
- He's set this up though, ain’t he? - Who, the gaffer?
没错
Yeah.
为了明天的比赛先给他们浇点油是吧
A little bit of nastiness in them for tomorrow?
确实
Yeah.
小孙啊，疼得厉害吗？
Sonny, is the pain very bad?
你能感觉到我在摸你的脚后跟不？
Can you feel me touching your heel OK?
来东东你的脚趾头，先动动看
Wiggle your toes, wiggle the toes first.
不是肌肉的问题的吧…应该就是前……
It’s not in muscle... it’s in the sh...
对的，小腿胫部，但是正好在胫骨旁边了
Yeah, it’s the shin, but it’s down the side of the bone
而且你看，软组织淤青开始慢慢浮现出来了
but also you can see the bruising coming up in the soft tissue underneath there.
为了培养球队，培养一种战术
To develop a team, to develop a style of play,
甚至说磨练一种精神
to develop even a mentality,
一定程度上就得用用这种损招
we need to use the difficult moments
让他们互相逼迫，互相责怪，甚至发生冲突
to push each other, to blame each other, to have confrontation.
这种事情发生了，是可以允许发生的，我也喜闻乐见
It happen, can happen and I like it to happen.
感觉还行不？
Feeling OK?
- 你他妈的图什么？  - 对不起，兄弟，真的对不起
- Why? - I'm sorry, hey. I'm sorry.
我就整不明白了
I don't get it.
试想一下，我胫骨要是断了怎么整
Imagine, I broke my shin.
受伤是一回事儿，疼一疼没事的
One thing is an injury, another thing is pain.
我们不是备着止痛药的嘛
That’s why we have painkillers.
小孙，来拍个照片，放到ins上
Sonny, take a picture, put in Instagram
来个标题 “震惊！热刺训练中心竟发生这种事情！”
and say, "This was in the training centre."
我发誓我真的生气了
So angry, I swear.
热刺接下来要面对的，是刚刚尝到甜头的埃弗顿
Facing Tottenham next is a resurgent Everton side.
对这场比赛你有多紧张，多兴奋？
How nervous, excited are you for this game?
我们还是没拿出精气神来，没那种赢家的精气神
We haven’t got the mentality, we haven’t got winning mentality.
这个男人是个赢家
This is a man that’s a winner,
无论他到哪，他都能为球队注入赢家精神
wherever he’s been, he's managed to instill a winning mentality.
怎么换成现在这帮球员，他就玩不转了呢？
Is that not possible, with this group of players he’s got?
小孙持球…
Here’s Son...
孙兴慜…
Son...
没传过去
No way through.
对阵谢菲联的比赛之后，他可能有坐下来跟队员们谈过
After the Sheffield United game, he's probably sat them down and said,
“兄弟们咱得硬起来啊，咱不只是要比这场强”
"Come on guys we really need, not only to be better than this,
“咱得拿出点斗志拿出点激情来”
but we also need to show a bit of fight and a bit of passion
“踢的更富有侵略性一点”
and a bit of aggression
“目前来看咱就是个软柿子”
because we are a soft touch."
温崽！果断一点！对！
Winksy, determination, yeah.
凯恩…
Kane...
洛塞尔索转身抽射！
Lo Celso on the turn...
漂亮的钻进球网！
And it's ended up in the back of the net.
卢卡斯，长传打高了，越过了孙兴慜的头顶
Lucas, with a loose ball over Son's head.
小孙没有在回追
Son isn't tracking back.
里查利森有机会…
Richarlison has a pop...
偏出太多了
A massive let off.
雨果·洛里仿佛一只任人宰割的羊羔
Hugo Lloris was left very exposed there.
看样子洛里把矛头指向了孙兴慜
And it looks like he is taking his frustrations out on Heung-min Son
冲突持续到了球员通道
and the discussions are continuing into the tunnel.
好了好了，没事了，没事了
It’s fine, it’s fine, it’s fine.
嘿！我他妈就操了！
Hey! Fucking hell!
不光是你，哈里也是
It’s the same for you, it’s the same for Harry,
卢卡斯也是，你们他妈的倒是跑起来啊！就他妈一分钟了！
it’s the same for Lucas, make the run! One minute to go!
半场结束就差一分钟我们还差点丢一个球
One minute to go and it nearly cost us a goal.
你倒是想让我们咋的？你想让我怎么着？
What should we do? What do you want me to do?
可以了，可以了
It's fine, it's fine.
他妈的话都让你给说了！
Because you say all this!
跑起来！跑起来啊！为了球队你们倒是跑啊！
Make the run, make the run, make the run for the team!
好
OK.
我简单说两句
Very, very quick.
刚才这里发生的一切
What happened in here,
我不知道你们是什么个情况，我听到他想让你回来协防
I don’t know the whole of the story, I know that he wants you to come back,
他喊你回追，然后你就…嘤嘤嘤嗯嗯啊啊汪汪汪
I know he wants you to come back but you…enenwawa
如果你们还把自己当小孩儿
but if you are a kid,
当那种娇生惯养的小孩儿
if you are a spoilt guy,
那就歇逼了
it's very bad.
你们能正确处理此事，你们会因此获得成长
If you take it in the right way, you become stronger.
可能在一个月前，两个月前
Probably this would be something that wouldn’t happen
一年前，两年前，这种事不会发生的
one month ago, two months ago, one year ago, two years ago.
之所以现在会有这种事，是因为你们对彼此的要求更高了
It happened because now you demand more from... from each other,
你们身上的责任感更重了，你们也会更努力的去拼了
you feel more the responsibility, where you have to give more.
我们担不起半场结束前最后一分钟丢球
We cannot concede a goal in the last minute of the first half
同样担不起全场结束前最后一分钟丢球
and we cannot concede a goal in the last minute of the second half,
所以说如果你们能以积极的方式化解矛盾，对我来说，非常完美
so if you take it in a positive way, for me, it’s perfect.
屁点大的事儿
For me, it’s perfect.
加油！嘿！冲啊！
Come on, hey. Let’s go!
洛塞尔索再次抢回球权
Lo Celso once again has won the ball well.
凶狠的铲断，动作幅度很大
There’s some big challenges in there.
美丽足球是一点都谈不上了，甚至很多人可能会用丑陋来形容
Wasn’t the prettiest, probably, someone would say it was ugly,
真刀真枪的激战，拳拳到肉
but there was plenty of fight in there, quite literally.
这是一场对热刺来说非常重要的胜利，三分收入囊中，这比什么都重要
Big win for Spurs, it was all about the three points today and Spurs get it.
当你身处比赛当中的时候，你知道，有时候
When you are in the action, you know, sometimes it’s difficult to manage
很难控制住自己的情绪，所以我当时有点失控
your emotions so that something that make me a bit out of control
但最好的解决办法就是握手言和，共同前行
but the best way is to shake the hand and to move on.
嗯，很多时候，在球场上咄咄逼人的恶汉
Uh, most of the time, the craziest guy on the pitch,
场下都是软萌的小泰迪
they are teddy bears on the life.
在这种时候，我们只要能赢就行
In moments like this, we have just to win.
第一个三分入账！咱后面有戏！
First three points, we are alive.
咱还有得踢！
We are alive!
我不是一个喜欢跟别人争执起冲突的人
I'm not a guy who like to fight or shout back.
嗯…
Uh...
当然了，对于雨果，我非常尊重他，无论是作为队长，球员还是为人
Of course, Hugo, I respect him so much as a captain, as a player, as a human.
当我在球场的时候，我会倾其所有的拼尽全力
If I am on the pitch, I will do everything if it’s possible,
我是那种会逼自己去拼的人，去赢得一切
I am the guy who wants work and who wants win everything.
足球世界里这种事情司空见惯的，我们的关系其实比家人还要亲密
And this is happen in football, we are like more than family
我们之间相处的时间，我也好，雨果也好
so we spend time I think, almost, with me, with Hugo,
已经有五六年了，这都是正常的
almost now six years, five years and I think it’s normal.
每当踏上球场的时候，每个人奔着当赢家去的
I don’t think we've ever gone on the pitch not wanting to win but sometimes,
但有时候为了赢得比赛，要学会放下骄傲
you have to take pride in winning scrappy games, ugly games,
你不可能常常比赛都完爆对手
you’re never going to always out-play the opposition.
总是追求每场都能赢得漂亮是不可能的
You’re never always gonna just, like, win by playing pretty football.
场上的十一个人沆瀣一气，团结一心
When you’ve got eleven people pulling in that same direction,
力往一处使，这比什么都重要
then it’s about the fight more than anything.
穆帅给了我们一些提点，我觉得都是非常重要的
José, he gave us a little bit of a wake up call so I think it was very important.
他所希望的是我们努力成为赢家，当然这也是我们所奋斗的方向
All he wants us to be is winners and I think that’s what we want to be
不断拼搏，努力去赢
going... going forward.
热刺对阵埃弗顿成功零封对手之后
Spurs follow a clean sheet against Everton,
对阵伯恩茅斯也成功零封
with another one against Bournemouth.
双方在活力球场互交白卷
It’s all over here goalless at the Vitality stadium.
但这一次他们没能取得进球，仅仅带走了一分
But this time they fail to score, taking just a point from the game.
他们现在积分榜排名第九
They are now in ninth place,
欧冠席位已经是遥不可及了
and are unlikely to qualify for the Champions League.
但争取欧联席位仍有一线希望
But there is still a chance they could qualify for the Europa League.
- 嘿，若泽  - 来吧，马特
- Hey, José. - Let's go, Matt.
球迷对这个赛季可谓相当的失望和愤怒
The fans are pretty frustrated and angry about the season,
他们愤怒的根源还是因为一支上赛季打入欧冠决赛的队伍
um, they’re just angry about the fact that a team and a club
一家这样的俱乐部，现在只能在英超的联赛积分榜里
that was in the Champions League final now sits in... in ninth position
屈居第九
in the Premier League table.
你能不能给球迷一些鼓励乐观的言论
Can you give them any encouragement or optimism
告诉他们只是这个赛季倒霉
that this is just a one-off bad season?
我认为我想传递出的信息已经非常简单了，就是说
I think the message is very, very simple, which is...
球迷们不开心，球队里也没有人开心的起来
supporters are not happy, nobody in this club is happy.
上赛季的欧冠决赛之后
I think that after Champions League final,
我认为决赛败北的苦果令他们难以下咽
I think was very, very difficult for them to digest.
当下很难很难去相信
Was very, very difficult to... to...
明天一觉醒来，太阳照常升起，仿佛无事发生
to believe that the next day, the sun would be shining again.
从那一刻开始，整个方向就
And from that moment, I think the direction was...
变得非常非常难
was very, very difficult.
然后在本赛季最关键的阶段
Then the accumulation of injuries in a crucial part of the...
伤病潮来势汹汹
of the season too.
加上埃里克森这样的核心球员
Also the situation of a very important player like Christian
拒绝与俱乐部续约
refusing to sign a new contract.
大俱乐部，总有起起伏伏的时候
Big clubs, they have moments of transition.
有时候他们会置换新的球员，有时候他们会…失去一些球员
They have moments of replacing players. They have moments of... of losing players.
唯一支撑我坚定乐观
The thing that keeps me strong and optimistic and
并对俱乐部和整个计划200%忠诚的关键因素是
200% loyal to the club and to the... to the project
我明确的之后俱乐部想要更进一步的野心
is to know that the club wants to improve.
你知道赢下德比战的重要性的
You know how important it is to win a derby match
尤其实在伦敦这块，热刺肯定想胜阿森纳一头
and obviously in this part of London, for Spurs to finish above Arsenal
就像过去的几年间一样
as they have in the last few years.
我们正在为我们尚且还能争取的东西奋斗
We are fighting for the only thing that we can fight for.
一分之差，还有四场比赛要踢
One point distance, four matches to go,
在此之上，还有这场德比
in the top of that, there is... there is a rivalry
毕竟终归到底，这家俱乐部是因球迷而建，也是为球迷而生
because in the end the club is... is made by and for the fans.
球迷们对这种比赛有着特殊的感情
And the fans, they have a special feeling for this match
所以场上的球员需要为球迷博上一切
so the people that is on the pitch has to fight for them.
热刺的下一场比赛毫无疑问是本赛季的重中之重
Tottenham’s next match is arguably their biggest of the season.
他们将面对熟悉的宿敌，阿森纳
They face their oldest rivals, Arsenal.
当两家俱乐部从地理上来说就门户相对
When there’s two teams who are literally right on the doorstep to each other,
显然火药味会相当浓烈，也就是北伦敦之战
obviously there’s gonna be a rivalry and it’s that fight for North London
对于俱乐部来说，对于球员来说，这绝对是一场非常重要的比赛
and it’s an important game for the club, for the players
但对于球迷而言，特殊意义更是无以复加
but for the fans, it’s just that extra special.
两家球队都想着弄死对方
Both teams love to beat each other.
每周的比赛你都会想赢，但是，你知道的
Every week you want to win, but yeah, you know what it means,
这样的比赛总是有着更深的意义的
it’s always got a special edge to it.
接下的所有比赛中
Out of the remaining fixtures,
这场比赛是球迷真正非常期待的
this is the one where the fans are really looking forward to.
对于球迷而言意义非凡
This is the one that means the most to them.
热刺与阿森纳之间的宿怨可以追溯到一百年前
The rivalry between Spurs and Arsenal began over a hundred years ago.
1913年，阿森纳从南伦敦搬到了海布里
In 1913, Arsenal moved from South London to Highbury.
距离托特纳姆仅有四英里
Just four miles from Tottenham.
阿森纳白嫖了一个名额进军顶级联赛
Arsenal were then awarded a place in the first division,
随之而来的代价就是热刺惨遭降级
at the expense of Spurs, who were relegated to make way.
接下来的22年里，阿森纳在联赛几乎都是踩着热刺踢
For 22 years, Arsenal had dominated Tottenham in the league.
传给凯恩！头球攻门！哈里·凯恩！
Towards Kane, there’s the header! Harry Kane...
但是近来热刺逐渐占据上风
But recently, Spurs have been coming out on top.
连续三个赛季力压阿森纳
And have finished above them for the past three seasons.
打门！球进了！
Goes for it... Oh yes!
漂亮！哈里·凯恩！
Oh yes, Harry Kane!
技惊四座的打门！
That is absolutely sensational.
我摸不清楚你们是咋想的哈
I don’t know if you have the same opinion as I have.
咱经历的都不一样
We have all different experiences
咱生涯里的比赛也好，尤其是德比战
in our careers of derbies and matches like this.
最重要的是理解比赛的意义
Most important thing is the way you understand the game,
你对比赛的感受，你准备好怎么做
the way you feel the game, what you are ready to do
个人来说也好，从球队来说也好
individually, collectively.
从积分榜来说，确实，你们知道比赛的意义
In terms of the table, of course, you know what it means,
这是我们争夺欧联席位的机会
is a opportunity to play Europa League is to win
得赢接下来的四场比赛
the four matches that we... that we have.
抛开这个不谈
But independent of that,
这比赛的意义…
what the game means for...
对俱乐部来说，对球迷来说，对每个人来说
for the club, for the fans, for everybody.
能赢的球队不见得是能力更强的
The team that win is not the team with more quality,
不见得是表现更好的
it’s not the best team, it’s not the team
也不见得是积分榜排名更高的
that is in a better position in... in the table.
而是对比赛感受更深刻的球队
It’s the team that feels the game more than the other.
我们真的得拼了，死磕到底，加油吧
And we have to fight, fight... Come on.
这是一场注定备受关注的比赛，日程表上要标注星号的那种比赛
It’s always a massive fixture. The biggest one on the calendar.
这可是北伦敦德比，谁不想赢呢
It is North London derby, it’s the one that we all want to win.
所以只能祈祷这帮球员能使出全力去比赛吧
So fingers crossed that they sort of come out and play.
埃里克·戴尔被禁赛四场
Eric Dier’s been banned for four games.
所以戴尔并不会出场
So Dier won’t be there.
我感觉缺少他是很难打的，因为他是整个队里
I think he’s a big miss because he’s the nearest thing
最能重拳出击、振臂怒吼、拼尽全力的人了
we’ve got to someone who’s gonna clench his fists and shout and really dig in.
北伦敦德比就是今天了
It’s North London derby day.
热刺将首次在托特纳姆热刺球场
Spurs face Arsenal at Tottenham Hotspur Stadium
迎战阿森纳
for the very first time.
两支球队在积分榜上争夺欧联席位只差一分
One point between them in the fight for Europe.
对于若泽·穆里尼奥和米克尔·阿尔特塔来说，这是他们的
For José Mourinho and Mikel Arteta, this is a first North London derby
第一场北伦敦德比
in the dugouts.
这已经无关联赛和其他因素了
It doesn’t matter about the league or anything like that,
就是要干他丫的，给丫按在地上锤
really we just want to beat them, we just want to finish above them.
这场比赛是所有人都在期待的，而且咱必须拿下
This game’s the one we’re all waiting for. This is the one we’ve got to win.
不为别的，咱就是为了这口气也得给他拿下
This is a game where the only thing to play for now is pride.
我们今天要是能赢，这赛季一笔勾销
If we win today, all if forgiven.
确实确实，咱今天要是给他拿下，发生了啥都不算个事儿
That's for sure, if we win today, I don’t care what happens.
只要今天能赢
We just need to win today.
球迷看台空无一人
The stands are empty,
球迷只能在家里为球队加油
fans can only watch and cheer from their homes.
卢卡斯·莫拉开场几秒钟就来了一脚
As Lucas Moura has a pop at goal inside the opening seconds.
小孙上啊！
Go Sonny!
孙兴慜搭档凯恩形成双前锋
Son, supporting Harry Kane as a second striker.
情况不妙，拉卡泽特拿到球了
He gets in a bit of trouble. Lacazette will drive it...
亚历山大·拉卡泽特！难以置信的进球！
It’s an unbelievably good goal from Alexandre Lacazette.
阿森纳在北伦敦德比首开纪录
And Arsenal have the lead in the North London derby.
压力来到了路易斯这边
Luiz, he’s under pressure!
噢！他丢球了！孙兴慜抓住了机会！
Oh, he’s lost it and Son has nicked in...
扳平比分的进球！
for what will be the equaliser.
来自孙兴慜的华丽一击
Brilliant work from Heung-min Son.
热刺几乎在电光火石间就扳平了比分
Spurs get level almost immediately.
本·戴维斯…
Ben Davies...
拔脚怒射！咣的一声正中横梁
decides to thump it at goal and it’s rattled into the bar.
塞尔吉·奥里耶领取黄色战神卡一张
And there will be a card for Serge Aurier.
三名热刺的球员吃牌了
Three Spurs players on cautions now.
来到半场休息，热刺1-1阿森纳
Half time. It's Tottenham Hotspur one, Arsenal one.
- 兄弟们，胜负在此一举  - 冲啊冲啊冲啊
- Boys, this is there for us.  - Come on, come on, come on.
别慌，认真阅读比赛，找到时机再向前冲
Stay, read the game. Feel the right moment to go.
冲的时候别磨磨唧唧的
But when you go, you go.
咱得跑起来
We need to force the run.
咱得主动给比赛提速
We need to force more the run.
好，如果球到这里，小孙拿到二点
OK, OK, the ball come here. Sonny gets the second ball,
传给卢卡斯，从这开始就得凶狠一点
plays to Lucas and then is when we have to be more aggressive.
进攻奔着射门去，要打出气势来
And, and, really go for the shot, really go for the action.
打击对方的空隙，逼迫他们犯错
Attack the space, force the mistake.
我让你们打击对方的空隙，你们一股脑冲出去
And when I say attack the space, you attack the space,
这时候二点得有人来接应
the second guy needs to be close.
我们一旦回传球
Every time we pass a ball back,
他们就会把三线往前压一点，不是很多，但每次咱都让他们得手了
every time they push, not a lot, but they always push.
咱得在防守上集中注意力
We have to defend with all of our focus.
但进攻才能赢得比赛
But the game is there to win.
伙计们上啊
Come on, lads. Come on.
兄弟们干他丫的！咱拼了！
Come on boys, we go for win, huh? We go for win, huh?
冲啊冲啊
Come on, come on.
- 热刺加油！  - 加油！
- Come on, Spurs! - Come on!
洛塞尔索用他的绝活儿给中场带来了活力
Lo Celso will spring into life here as he loves to do.
球给的漂亮，精准的传球找到了卢卡斯·莫拉！
And that’s a great ball, great work from him to find Lucas Moura.
洛塞尔索的活跃打开了球场的空挡
Pitch has been opened up here by Lo Celso.
卢卡斯对阵穆斯塔菲
Lucas Moura driving for Mustafi...
塞瓦略斯
Ceballos...
脚后跟传给佩佩，热刺有点陷入被动
back heels to Pepe, that bamboozled Spurs a little bit.
佩佩
Pepe...
好样的，小孙冲啊！
OK, OK, come on, Sonny!
凯恩
Kane...
硬刚过掉了穆斯塔菲，他能找到孙兴慜吗
muscles his way beyond Mustafi. Can he stab it in to Son?
我了个大草！什么鬼！
No! How?
马丁内兹做出扑救，凯恩倒地
Martínez makes a save, Kane is down.
比赛来到了最后十分钟
Into the final ten minutes.
卢卡斯·莫拉，找到了跑位中的凯恩
Here's Lucas Moura, sees the run of Kane.
漂亮的打门！可惜马丁内兹及时出击扑了出去
Fantastic ball and Martínez was sharp off his line.
漂亮的头球破门！
Oh, the header's into the net!
热刺取得了领先！
And Spurs have taken the lead!
托比·阿尔德维雷尔得肆意庆祝！
Toby Alderweireld is the man celebrating
比赛结束前最后的十分钟里！
into the final ten minutes of the game!
北伦敦德比迟到的绝杀进球！
And it’s a late, late goal in the North London derby.
托比·阿尔德维雷尔得高高跃起将球漂亮的顶进死角
Toby Alderweireld was there to guide it into the corner brilliantly.
比赛结束
It's over.
热刺在新球场拿下了第一场北伦敦德比的胜利
Spurs win the first North London derby at the new stadium
带走了对于争夺欧联席位至关重要的三分
and it’s a massive three points in the fight for European football.
托特纳姆热刺2-1阿森纳
Tottenham Hotspur two, Arsenal one.
- 爽的一笔！  - 牛逼啊！
- Woo! Yes! - Come on!
牛逼！
Yes!
热刺牛逼！
Come on you Spurs!
咱就是他妈的牛逼！
Yes, yes, yes!
爽爆了！
Bravo!
北伦敦一片欢声笑语，而接下来的消息则更令人兴奋
It’s all smiles in North London and there are more reasons to be cheerful.
托特纳姆本土出产的热刺后卫，贾菲特·坦甘加
As Spurs defender, and Tottenham local, Japhet Tanganga
与球队签下一份五年的长约
is signing a new five-year deal.
我跟我的家人都非常兴奋，而且
I’m excited and you know for my family as well and honestly,
我爸也在那，这对我们大家都说都是个令人兴奋的时刻
my dad’s there and for all of us, it’s just an exciting moment.
不是我说啊，你俩看起来好像没那么开心嘛
If you don’t mind me saying, neither of you look very happy...
好嘞
There you go.
从他五岁开始我就知道了，这孩子有足球上的天赋
I knew this since when he was five, he had the skills of football.
他带球的时候
He was like...
就跟台机器一样
a machine when he's running with the ball.
很多大俱乐部当时都在追求他
All the big clubs were chasing him.
我们到了阿森纳
We came to Arsenal.
他们说，“我们希望他能成为一名阿森纳球员”
They said, "We want him to be an Arsenal player."
好在我们找到了一个热刺的人
Luckily we found a person from Tottenham.
“明天把他带来托特纳姆球场，我们要定他了”
"Bring him tomorrow,
at Tottenham, we like him."
周六，我们就对阵阿森纳来了一场
Saturday, we had a game against Arsenal,
他进球了，我记得是两球来着
so he scored, I think, two goals.
比赛结束当场他们就拿合同来找他签了
Straight away after the match, they gave us the contract and he signed.
咱这里也跟贾菲特来两张？
Shall we do a couple of pictures with Japhet here?
好
Yeah.
我觉得他应该知道，我对他和对整个家庭有多感激
I think he knows how grateful I am of not only him but my whole family.
每个人都在为我付出，努力，才能成就我的今天
Everyone has chipped in and played a part for me to be in this moment today.
这仅仅是一个开始
This is just the beginning.
从现在开始，我要继续努力付出
This is the just the start and from here just to kick on,
保持对进步的渴望，继续我被派上场对战利物浦
just making sure I stay hungry and keep doing the things
那时候背后的努力
that got me to play against Liverpool.
按照教练的要求去做，保持进步
Keep doing what the manager asks, keep improving and make sure
我还不能骄傲自满，毕竟我还没有功成名就
I don’t get complacent and I don’t think I’ve made it
还需要继续的去努力
and I don’t need to try anymore
这才是对我而言最重要的
so that’s the big one for me.
我们对贾菲特和他本赛季的进步感到非常的欣喜
We're excited about Japhet and the way he's progressed this season.
我们有一群非常优秀的年轻球员
We’ve got a good group of good young players,
没准夏天我们还能再添置两到三个球员，甚至更多
hopefully, we will add two or three players this summer, maybe more.
但对于球迷而言是很难理解的，球迷总是说
It’s difficult for fans because fans always say,
“我们得签下这个球员，我们得签下那个球员”
"We should be signing this player, we should be signing that player."
我们的转会预算非常充足
We've been backed in terms of transfer funds,
我们也知道球队的弱点在哪，与强队的差距在哪，若泽也很清楚
we know the holes, the gaps. I think José is very clear
球队里大概有三到四个位置是他重点想要补强的
that there is three to four positions he wants to improve on.
我们总是跟青训营保持无间合作
We work together always in cohesion with the academy,
若泽，丹尼尔，我们都有一个长远的计划
with José, with Daniel, with a long-term plan.
冲啊塞斯！干得不错！
Go on Sess! Yes, Sess!
我认为这就是我们跟其他俱乐部不一样的地方
And I think that is the difference between us and other clubs
我们更加着眼于未来，而不是仅仅聚焦于当下
that we've got to always look further down the line rather than today.
今晨传来关于曼城的大消息
Big news for Manchester City later on this morning, they'll learn
他们将很快知晓他们对禁止其参加欧战赛事两年的禁令
whether their appeal against that two-year ban from European club
上诉的结果是否成功
competitions has been successful.
要知道他们之所以被处以禁令
You will remember they were banned from European football,
是因为他们被查到严重违法欧足联俱乐部运营执照
after being found to have committed serious breaches of UEFA’s club licensing
和财政公平法案
and financial fair play regulations.
本台将持续为您报道前方最新消息
We'll bring it to you, of course, as soon as we hear news of it.
国际体育仲裁法庭推翻了关于曼城的欧战禁赛令
CAS have overturned Manchester City's European ban
意味着他们在明年跟后年
which means that they can participate
都能去踢欧冠了
in the Champions League in the next two years.
啥子？哪儿的消息？
What? Where is that?
官媒
Official media.
官媒？
Official?
取消掉了，没有禁赛令了
They’ve lifted it, there is no ban.
- 卧槽没了？  - 确实没了
- No ban?  - No ban.
- 曼城是吧？  - 嗯
- Man City? - Yeah.
取消曼城禁赛令的决定
The decision to overturn Manchester City’s ban
意味着如果要想争夺下赛季的欧联席位
means that to guarantee Europa League football next season,
热刺至少需要保住第六
Tottenham must finish sixth.
他们目前积分榜排名第八，离赛季结束仅剩三场比赛
They currently sit eighth, with only three games to go.
咱得都赢下来了
We have to win everything.
三场比赛全部梭哈
We need to win three games.
热刺今年只在客场赢过一场比赛
Spurs have only won away from home once this year.
下一轮是客战纽卡斯尔
Next up is a trip to Newcastle.
咱三场全赢，欧联到手
We win the three matches, we get Europa League.
赢球了，咱就有的踢
If we win our matches, we are there.
所以不多哔哔了，必须拿下
We have to win, so no more talk.
孙兴慜
Son...
华丽的进球！正中靶心！
What a wonderful strike! It’s absolutely spot on.
贝尔温起脚传中
Bergwijn's delivery...
凯恩头球精彩命中！
Harry Kane with an excellent header.
热刺全取三分
Tottenham take all three points,
哈里·凯恩梅开二度
with Harry Kane scoring two
将自己的职业生涯总进球数提升到了200球以上
to take his tally to over two hundred career goals.
200球是一种神奇的体验
Two hundred goals is just an amazing feeling.
职业生涯中会经历大大小小的里程碑时刻
During your career you kind of go through landmarks like that
当时可能都没有什么感觉，但等到我退役
and you don’t fully take it in. It will be when I finish playing,
会看我的职业生涯，才会发现原来已经达到了这么多成就
you look back and you realise what you have actually done.
对于我而言，我达到了200球里程碑
For me, I’ve scored two hundred goals
但更重要的是，什么时候我能打进我的下100个进球，甚至下200个进球
but it’s about how quickly can I get the next hundred, or next two hundred.
今日哈里的妻子和他们的两个女儿来训练中心看望他
Today Harry’s wife and two daughters have joined him at the training centre
共同与他们的家人和朋友见证他们第三个孩子的性别
to reveal the gender of his third child to his friends and his family.
- 爸比！  - 咱都怎么想的呀？
- Daddy! - What we all thinking?
- 男孩子，我估计是个男孩子  - 我也觉得
- Boy, I think boy. - Boy.
我觉得当你的个人生活非常顺利的时候
I think there’s a big part of it when your personal life is going well,
很大程度上也能推动你的职业生涯顺利走下去
it definitely relates to your professional life as well.
爸比？
Daddy?
爸爸要去命中那个球了，你们兴奋不？
Daddy's gonna go and kick the ball now. Are you excited?
- 想要个啥颜色的？  - 粉色！
- What colour do you want? - Pink!
- 粉色嘛？ - 薇薇呢？
- Pink? - What about you, Vivi?
- 蓝色  - 你俩一个要蓝色，一个要粉色
- Blue. - You want blue, you want pink.
我一直让凯特也别看那封信，所以说
I’ve been keeping Kate away from the letter so,
绝对的大惊喜，绝对的
this a complete surprise, really.
讲道理，一点线索都没有反而更加令人期待
Honestly, ain't got a clue what it’s going to be so we're excited.
你们觉得爸爸会命中嘛？嗯？
Do you think Daddy's gonna score a goal? Yeah?
爸爸加油！爸比加油！
Go Daddy! Daddy, go!
这球比我想象中要小啊
That ball looks smaller than I thought.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
噢！是个男孩儿！
Oh, it's a boy!
薇薇！是个男孩儿！
Oh, it's a boy, Vivi!
- 哈里，感觉如何？ - 惊喜不？
- How you feeling, Harry? - Shocked?
惊喜，确实，我太惊喜了，完全是个大惊喜
Shocked, yeah. I'm really surprised. I'm really surprised.
我一直都以为会是个女儿
I was adamant it was going to be a girl.
是男孩儿是吗？
Is it a boy?
天哪
Oh, my God.
- 再来一个小女孩儿！  - 你爹想也没有啊！
- Do a little girl now. - I can't do a little...
还指望啥呐！你妈妈就怀了这一个崽！
That's it! There's no more.
场下的生活非常的精彩，场上也一样
Things are exciting off the pitch and they’re exciting on the pitch as well.
我们赛季末的表现非常出色，所以希望我们能争取到欧联席位吧
We're finishing strong so hopefully we can get a Europa League spot
下赛季至少还能四线作战
and at least be in four competitions next year.
热刺的下一个三分所要面临的对手
Standing in the way of another three points,
同时也是本赛季的最后一次主场作战的对手
in the final home match of the season,
是欧冠席位的有力竞争者，莱斯特城
are Champions League hopefuls, Leicester City.
来吧，大家都清楚自己的任务
Come on, everybody know your jobs.
进军欧联就看这一场了，兄弟们，重中之重
Big step to go to Europe. Big step, right here.
就在今天了，今儿就是决胜局，决胜局！今儿高低也得赢下来！
It's a final, it's a final, it's a final. It's a final today, win or win.
我们能赢的
Yeah, we'll win.
一锤定音了，加油！
Massive game, come on!
凯恩牢牢地拿住了球，漂亮的传给小孙
Here is Kane to hold it up and he’s done really well to set away Son.
孙兴慜
Heung-min Son...
晃到了本内特！热刺首开纪录！
leaves Bennet on the floor and Spurs have got an early lead.
精彩的配合造就的第二个进球！
And it’s a brilliantly constructed second goal.
凯恩打门！非比寻常的进球！
Kane will score, something truly special.
热刺正在为本赛季画上一个有力的句号
Spurs are finishing the campaign very strongly
八天打赢了三场比赛
and have won three in the space of eight days.
恭喜你们再下一城，非常全面的表现
Congratulations on the win. I mean, that seemed quite comprehensive really.
你怎么评价球队今天的表现
What did you make of the performance today?
我对球队非常欣慰，因为这场比赛的压力非常大
I am very happy because it’s a game with a lot of pressure to us,
我们拼到了最后一刻
and we are fighting until we can.
一分接着一分，一场接着一场，马上就是最终战了
Point after point, match after match and seeing the end.
热刺主场的收官战以胜利告终
Spurs are victorious in their last home game.
今天，球队主席和教练
And today, the Chairman and Head Coach
将在球馆的天花板上鸟瞰整座球场和伦敦的天际线
are getting a bird’s eye view of the stadium and the London sky line.
行不？
OK?
- 感觉还行不？  - 能行
- Feel OK? - Yeah.
我倒不是恐高
I’m not bad with heights,
就是当你俯视去看你原本熟悉的东西，会有一点点奇怪
it's only when I look down that sometimes, I feel a bit strange.
- 若泽，你恐高不？  - 我恐高
- José, are you good with heights? - No.
淦
No.
他们将被带上屋顶
They're about to be taken up on to the roof,
距离球场地面150英尺
a hundred and fifty feet above the pitch
他们将成为球场“勇闯天涯”项目的首批体验者
and be amongst the first to try out The Dare Skywalk.
你说我要不要先给球队交代一下周天怎么搞，以往万一我就交代在这了
Do you want me to tell the team for Sunday in case I don’t come back?
我感觉VAR比这个还恐怖
I think VAR is more scary than this.
你明明进球了还得在那等，算是不算
When you score a goal and you are there waiting, goal, no goal.
以我们热刺的体量来讲，咱们的球员跟球迷
Tottenham is a size of a club that our players and our fans
都希望我们，也都习惯了我们每年有欧战踢
expect us, and have got used to us being in Europe,
但是你也知道，咱这个赛季过的那是一个难上加难
but you know, we have had a very, very difficult season.
所以我觉得以这种成绩收官，虽然不是那么的令人满意
So I think to end up in a place, not that it’s satisfactory,
但至少，咱还有欧战能踢
um, but to end up still being in Europe,
在这种情况之下，我觉得吧，也是一个能接受的成绩
I think, in the circumstances, will be a good place to end up.
噢！
Oh!
幸好我有个东西可以抓着
I'm glad I got something to hold onto.
这地方最合适把经纪人带来谈判了
It’s the best place to bring the agents to negotiate.
哟，那是爷的教练席，额滴个乖乖
Oh, look at my bench. Oh, my god.
牛逼普拉斯
Incredible.
我向来每年都是有欧战踢的，所以我也不希望这是我头一遭
I always qualified for Europe so I don’t want to be the first time
欧战没得踢
of not qualifying for Europe.
于我，于球员，于球迷来说，都是非常重要的
It’s very important for me, for the players, for the fans,
对俱乐部的每一个人来说都是
for the club, for everybody.
对于球员的精神层面，保持这种骄傲也是非常非常重要的
But for the mental, by the pride side, it’s very, very important.
来到赛季的收官战，热刺在积分榜排名第八
Going into the last match, Tottenham sit in eighth.
狼队目前暂时以一分领先，热刺只要能比狼队踢得好
If they can secure a better result than Wolves, who are just one point ahead,
他们就能顺利确保进军下赛季的欧联杯
they will guarantee themselves a place in next season's Europa League.
你们都吭哧瘪肚12个月了
You are working for twelve months.
从他妈的去年6月份开始
Fucking since July.
加油，就没理由咱不给自己个交代
Come on, it's impossible we don't do it.
来吧来吧，嘿！冲啊！给爷冲！
Come on, hey! Let’s go, hey! Let’s go!
兄弟们！干他们，冲就完了！
Let's go. Let's go, boys!
对热刺来说，本赛季格外的非比寻常、跌宕起伏
For Spurs, it has been the most unusual and dramatic of campaigns.
一路从停摆、波切蒂诺下课、穆里尼奥接任
Along with the lockdown, Pochettino’s departure and Mourinho’s arrival,
埃里克森转会，阿尔德维雷尔得续约，凯恩、孙兴慜、洛里、西索科接连受伤
Eriksen leaving, Alderweireld staying, injuries to Kane, Son, Lloris and Sissoko.
太多太多故事了，但是在穆里尼奥麾下的第一个完整赛季
Too many stories to mention, but claiming Europa League football
成功进军下赛季的欧联杯
ahead of a first full season under Mourinho
也算是一个不错的方式来结束2019/20赛季
would be a good way to end 2019/20.
西索科…凯恩…
Sissoko... Kane...
精准找到卢卡斯，孙兴慜在中路跑位绝佳
well-weighted into Lucas Moura. Now Son’s made a good run into the middle.
洛塞尔索
Here’s Lo Celso...
一脚劲射
who will have a crack at goal.
目前切尔西0-0狼队，所以狼队暂位列积分榜第六
Chelsea nil, Wolves nil currently so Wolves is hanging onto sixth.
他们只要比热刺的结果强就行
They only have to match Spurs result.
洛塞尔索，直塞凯恩
Lo Celso slips in Kane...
打门！手起刀落！
who pulls the trigger in emphatic fashion.
典型的哈里·凯恩式进球
Typical Harry Kane.
那么热刺暂时来到了积分榜第六
So, at the moment Spurs are moving up to sixth.
卢卡斯·莫拉
Lucas Moura...
找到了空挡，他能拿到球吗，他拿到了！
looks to spring into a gap, will he meet the ball? Yes, he does.
漂亮！
That was brilliant work.
来到中场休息
It is half time,
顺便一提，来自斯坦福桥的突发新闻
and by the way, breaking news from Stamford Bridge,
切尔西对狼队拔得头筹
Chelsea have taken the lead against Wolves.
无疑是利好热刺的消息
That’s great news for Spurs.
如果局面持续到比赛结束，热刺将挺进欧联
If it all stays like this, Spurs are going into the Europa League.
咱防的不错，但是还得控制住比赛局面
We are defending quite well but we need to control the game.
咱得更为稳定一点
We need to be more, more consistent.
如果联赛现在就收官
If the league finished now,
咱能捞到一个第六
in this moment, we are sixth,
但是咱得赢下比赛，随时可能有新的变局
but we need to win the game. The game can go in two directions.
加油兄弟们！加油！
Come on, lads. Come on!
看样子只要一场平局热刺就能安稳收官
As things stand even a draw would be enough for Spurs
因为狼队目前0-2落后
because Wolves are trailing two-nil.
穆里尼奥已经知道之一消息了，但他不想让他的球员分心
And Mourinho will know the score line, but he will want his players to focus.
我们的球！
Our ball!
奥里耶在角旗区遭到紧逼
Serge Aurier under real pressure near the corner flag.
解围！再来！
Away! Again!
热刺惨遭当头棒喝
And it’s a big blow for Spurs.
热刺目前输不起
Spurs cannot afford to lose here,
因为但凡他们输一个，他们都保不住第六了
because if they lose, they will not claim sixth
斯坦福桥那边干啥都不顶用
no matter what happens at Stamford Bridge.
乔尔·沃德
Joel Ward...
噢！再次命中横梁
Oh, it's hit against the frame of the goal.
看球啊！
Look, look the ball!
这个位置危险了，阿尤
Precarious position this, Ayew!
现在进入伤停补时阶段
So we are now into added time.
水晶宫的球
It will be a Palace ball.
危险的传球
Delivery is dangerous...
稍稍偏出
and it's just wide.
全场比赛结束哨响，狼队保持落后，已经足够了
That is the full-time whistle and with Wolves losing, this will be enough.
穆里尼奥和他的主教团队正在庆祝
Mourinho and his coaching staff are celebrating.
我作为教练已经有点被惯坏了，因为我的职业生涯早就习惯了
I’m quite a spoilt coach because my career was always about
赢冠军，赢冠军，赢冠军
winning trophies, winning trophies, winning trophies.
我还从来没想象过自己会为了赛季末排名第六而兴高采烈
I would never imagine myself celebrating in the end of the season finishing sixth,
但是我把他们从十四名带到了第六名
but to arrive fourteenth and to finish sixth,
也还算不错是吧？
a good achievement?
至少我自己是这么认为的
I would say so.
[♪ AJ Tracey & Mabel: “West Ten”]
我接手热刺的时候，热刺是一家比现在小得多的俱乐部
Tottenham when I took over was a much smaller club than it is today,
我看着这家俱乐部就像一头沉睡中的猛兽
I saw this club as a club that was really a sleeping giant.
咱现在到了这个阶段得赢点什么了
We are now in a period where we need to win.
讲道理，我一直是个热刺球迷，我希望俱乐部越来越好
You know, I’m a spurs fan and I want to see this club continue to grow
我也想要看到冠军头衔
and I want to see trophies.
各位，我稍微说两句哈
Can I just have your attention for a minute, please?
首先，我想要感谢大家在这个艰难的赛季的所有付出
Firstly, I want to, uh, thank you all for what has been a difficult season
无论是场上还是场下
both on and off the pitch,
无论世界上今天发生了啥
and what’s going on in the world today.
咱以一个不错的成绩收官，我个人还是很满意的
I’m very pleased that we're finishing the season in a good place
但咱们队里有两个队员
but two members of our team,
很遗憾下赛季不会再跟我们并肩作战了
as we know, won’t be back next year, unfortunately.
来吧，米歇尔、杨，你俩上来吧
So Michel and Jan, I would like you to come up here.
你们两个人都毫无疑问是球队的铁血功勋
Both you guys have been an absolute credit to this club,
我们非常感谢你们的付出，这里随时欢迎你们回来
we would like to thank you very much, you are always welcome back.
无论你们将来的决定是什么，我们都衷心祝愿你们一路都好
Wish you both the best of luck in whatever you decide to do,
我们给你们买了个小礼物
and we have a small gift that we bought both of you.
一人一块手表，背后还会给你们刻字
We bought you both a watch and we'll get something engraved
专属定制
on the back for you.
非常感谢大家
Thank you very much.
这赛季着实是不容易
I think this season is a difficult one,
但未来会越来越好的，我会永远想念大家
the future will be bright and I’m going to miss everyone.
感谢你们所作的一切
So, thank you for everything.
非常感谢大家，八年前我刚来的时候
Thank you very much, I came here eight years ago
跟现在大不一样
in a total different environment.
这些年很多东西都变了，无论是作为俱乐部还是作为球队
A lot has changed over the years, where we are now as a club, as a team,
我为大家而骄傲
you have made me very proud.
大家对我来说意义非凡
You guys mean so much to me,
我很确定未来我没办法再找到这样的一直球队了
I know for sure I will never find a team like this again.
我一般不怎么看球，完整看完一场90分钟的球赛
I don’t watch a lot of football. I think in total 90 minutes I watch,
我印象中一个赛季不超过五次
not even five games a season,
但是下个赛季我会尽可能的收看每一场热刺的比赛
but I will watch every Spurs game that I can next season.
大都知道，球迷们管你叫超人詹
As we know, the fans call you Super Jan,
所以大伙儿也给你准备了一个礼物
so we’ve also got a gift that’s actually from all your teammates.
他们比赛之后我会给每个人打Facetime的，我一定会
I know, everyone I will FaceTime them after the game, I definitely know I will.
他们下赛季很有机会赢下大把的冠军奖杯
And they have got good chances of winning something next season
所以也祝他们一切都好
so hopefully for them they can now.
我会一直关注他们的，这会是一种很特别的感觉
And yeah, I will follow them and it will be very special.
热刺在过去的12个月里踢了52场比赛，史无前例最长的赛季
Spurs have played 52 games over 12 months, the longest season in their history.
一个跌宕起伏的赛季，跟做过山车一样
An up and down season, been of a rollercoaster of a season,
从我个人的角度来说，伤病这些东西都是这种感觉
obviously from a personal point of view of being injured and things like that.
但是从球队的角度来说
And just from a team point of view, whenever
赛季初是一个教练，赛季结束换成了另一个
you start with one manager and finish with another,
那这注定是一个不平凡的赛季
it means it’s going to be a strange season.
我们这赛季经历了不少困难的低谷，这没什么掩饰的
There's no hiding the fact that we went through a few difficult spells,
但是你环顾四周，看看咱球队这个实力
and when we look at the quality we have in the team and around the place,
所有东西，从训练场到球场，每一样东西，我觉得
everything we have from training ground to stadium, everything is, I think,
咱就是欧冠级别的
you know, the quality is Champions League.
没拿到前四诚然令人难过
To not get the top four, it was painful
毕竟欧冠是每个球员每个赛季都想踢的比赛
because Champions League everyone wants to play every season,
但至少我们还有欧联杯可以踢
but at least the minimum you get is Europa League
但愿我们能赢下点冠军奖杯，毕竟实力在这
and hopefully we will win some trophies because the quality is there
跟着教练走下去肯定能行的，我丝毫不怀疑
but I’m sure with this manager, we will do it.
我非常期待下赛季的开踢，因为
I look forward to the beginning of next season because
这几个月来我们的相处，我们的付出
everything we did, all these months that we spent together,
我觉得在未来都会收获回报的
I think are very, very important for the future.
我们已经准备好作为一个强大的集体面对任何困难了
We are ready to go through everything like a strong family
这是一个坚实的基础
and that creates us a good base,
但我想做到更好
but I want it to be better.
更好的成果
Better results.
更好的足球
Better football.
我们正在努力赢下冠军江北
We have to try to win a title
下赛季一定会更好的
and next season it is going to be better.